<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>黑客新闻：最佳评论</title><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments<description>黑客新闻 RSS</description><docs> https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>人力资源服务 v2.1.1</generator><lastbuilddate> 2024 年 1 月 21 日星期日 21:55:33 +0000 </lastbuilddate><atom:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by matejn in "Password may not contain: select, insert, update, delete, drop"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>噢！我把那根绳子放在那里了！这是管理层的要求，但我仍然不知道为什么。该网站不存储任何密码，它基本上只是外部帐户管理的一个很好的界面。<p>我听说有传言称，一些旧版应用程序的登录字段有奇怪的验证，因此学生无法使用包含某些字符串的密码登录。但我实际上不知道任何例子。</p> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 21 Jan 2024 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate><link/> https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39079030<dc:creator>马泰因</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39079030</comments><guid ispermalink="false"> https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39079030 </guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by matsemann in "Password may not contain: select, insert, update, delete, drop"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>不能包含“脚本”。<p>我在十几岁的时候就黑了一个大型社交平台（Nettby.no），因为他们刚刚删除了所有禁止的单词，包括<script>. I instead wrote <scr<script>ipt> in my profile bio, and after their removal I had a valid html tag injected into the webpage and full control of anyone visiting my page..</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 14:32:04 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078748<dc:creator>matsemann</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078748</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078748</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by gfodor in "Nightshade: An offensive tool for artists against AI art generators"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Huge market for snake oil here. There is no way that such tools will ever win, given the requirements the art remain viewable to human perception, so even if you made something that worked (which this sounds like it doesn’t) from first principles it will be worked around immediately.<p>The only real way for artists or anyone really to try to hold back models from training on human outputs is through the law, ie, leveraging state backed violence to deter the things they don’t want. This too won’t be a perfect solution, if anything it will just put more incentives for people to develop decentralized training networks that “launder” the copyright violations that would allow for prosecutions.<p>All in all it’s a losing battle at a minimum and a stupid battle at worst. We know these models can be created easily and so they will, eventually, since you can’t prevent a computer from observing images you want humans to be able to observe freely.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 19:53:47 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071577<dc:creator>gfodor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071577</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071577</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by 542458 in "Nightshade: An offensive tool for artists against AI art generators"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>This seems to introduce levels of artifacts that many artists would find unacceptable: <a href="https://twitter.com/sini4ka111/status/1748378223291912567" rel="nofollow">https://twitter.com/sini4ka111/status/1748378223291912567</a><p>The rumblings I'm hearing are that this a) barely works with last-gen training processes b) does not work at all with more modern training processes (GPT-4V, LLaVA, even BLIP2 labelling [1]) and c) would not be especially challenging to mitigate against even should it become more effective and popular. The Authors' previous work, Glaze, also does not seem to be very effective despite dramatic proclamations to the contrary, so I think this might be a case of overhyping an academically interesting but real-world-impractical result.<p>[1]: Courtesy of /u/b3sn0w on Reddit: <a href="https://imgur.com/cI7RLAq" rel="nofollow">https://imgur.com/cI7RLAq</a> <a href="https://imgur.com/eqe3Dyn" rel="nofollow">https://imgur.com/eqe3Dyn</a> <a href="https://imgur.com/1BMASL4" rel="nofollow">https://imgur.com/1BMASL4</a></p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 15:38:26 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068620<dc:creator>542458</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068620</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068620</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by swozey in "Spotube: Open-source Spotify-Youtube client"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>The lengths that literal engineers will go to to not have to pay $10/mo for music or $3 to rent a movie in 4k immediately.<p>Can't believe I have adult friends who make 70-300k and they still pirate based on money, not quality/directors-cuts/anti-cheats, etc. I quit pirating when I got a real job and could afford to pay developers and movie teams for their effort.<p>I write software. I want to get paid too, right? Why shouldn't they?<p>And I pirated EVERYTHING as a kid/teenager. I had no money. Sketch Russian warez site? I'm in!</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 14:37:32 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067937<dc:creator>swozey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067937</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067937</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by bayindirh in "Spotube: Open-source Spotify-Youtube client"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Nifty.<p>Please be aware that this is not a "spotify client" per se. It gets the data from Spotify, and plays the audio from YouTube.<p>It's an interesting invention, and worthy of the first page, if you ask me.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:25:14 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066175<dc:creator>bayindirh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066175</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066175</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by jonathanlydall in "What's that touchscreen in my room?"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>A few years ago I came to the realisation that if you want people to be more environmentally conscious or economical in terms of utility consumption, (electricity, water, gas, etc), they need far better data than a single figure per month.<p>You want to be able to see usage to a resolution of at most 5 minutes.<p>That way people can spot things like “having my electric heater on for those couple of hours used more electricity than all my lights use for a month”.<p>I have an inverter and solar panels in my place (very common now in South Africa middle class homes due to unreliable electricity producer) and I can see a full history of electricity usage.<p>It’s easy for me to see where I can improve my efficiency or why my consumption was so high.<p>It’s still only an overall figure though, so you have to do an informed assumption as to what caused the consumption.<p>For example it’s obvious that the 3kw draw for about an hour or so after I shower is the geyser heating itself back up. I can see from the usage stats that my battery was depleted from the night, that the solar production is still low due to my showering in the early morning and that the energy was thus coming from the grid (the inverter records all these figures).<p>It is then obvious that I can very simply save money on electricity by putting a timer on my geyser so that it only heats after 10am or so, once the sun is high enough for solar production to cover the energy usage.<p>Now I just wish I had something as convenient for monitoring water consumption.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 07:02:35 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065359<dc:creator>jonathanlydall</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065359</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065359</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by josu in "What's that touchscreen in my room?"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>>DATE & TIME ARE ALWAYS CORRECT AND NEVER NEED TO BE ADJUSTED<p>Reads like a quote from a Philip K. Dick book.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 01:08:49 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063570<dc:creator>josu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063570</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063570</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by rmm in "Thailand discovers nearly 15M tonnes of lithium"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>This is my wheelhouse (mining engineer) and sorry to say this is bunk from what i can see.<p>Its not 15M Tonnes of Lithium. Its 15M Tonnes of lithium containing ore, with an average grade of 0.4% (which i also question without seening core results).<p>Also terms such as "resource" and "reserve" have very specific meaning in mining (to do with economic viability of deposity/ level of confidence) and this is by no way a "reserve".<p>Most likely overzealous government minister/media hyper. (sorry to rain on parade!)</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 23:57:14 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063078<dc:creator>rmm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063078</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063078</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by LeoPanthera in "Surf the web like it's 1999"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>If you set your HTTP proxy to "theoldnet.com" with port 1999, and add an exclusion for "web.archive.org", then all your web pages will come from 1999, via the Wayback Machine.<p>You can pick a different year by changing the port.<p>Edit: It may have been hugged to death...</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 18:03:03 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058806<dc:creator>LeoPanthera</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058806</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058806</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by maliker in "Thailand discovers nearly 15M tonnes of lithium"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Looks like existing worldwide reserves are 26M tons [0], so this is a big find.<p>[0] <a href="https://pubs.usgs.gov/periodicals/mcs2023/mcs2023-lithium.pdf" rel="nofollow">https://pubs.usgs.gov/periodicals/mcs2023/mcs2023-lithium.pd...</a></p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 17:34:29 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058286<dc:creator>maliker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058286</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058286</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by tiffanyh in "Apple Vision Pro available for pre-order"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>> When the iPad was introduced, everyone was shocked by the very low price and the sleek form factor compared to previous Windows tablet devices.<p>I remember history a bit differently.<p>I recall lots of people dismissing the iPad as "<i>just</i> a big iPod Touch".</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 13:42:59 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39055287<dc:creator>tiffanyh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39055287</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39055287</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by cousin_it in "Mourning Google"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>I have a different theory about the cause of the decline.<p>Google 10-15 years ago had a clear idea of how to win: hire the best programmers, give them freedom, and they'll build products that will win in every market. And, well, that hasn't happened. Long before the current talk of Google's decline, there was talk of the Google black hole, where talented people would get hired and their noteworthy output would drop to zero. It turned out hiring great programmers wasn't enough by itself, not many amazing new products were happening. That's what caused Google to change culture toward the corporate norm: the non-normal culture wasn't proving itself.<p>It reminds me of Fitzgerald's "Tender Is the Night". When you're young, that book is a tragedy of broken love. But when you're a bit older, you realize it's a tragedy of ambition, of a man who dreamed of becoming a famous psychiatrist but it just wasn't working out, year after year after year. And it wears on him, drives him to drinking and divorce. Simple as that.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 10:56:41 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39054021<dc:creator>cousin_it</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39054021</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39054021</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by sir in "Winding down Google Sync and Less Secure Apps support"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>If you can’t switch to OAuth, you can use my proxy to allow any IMAP (or POP/SMTP) client to be used with a “modern” email provider, regardless of whether the client supports OAuth 2.0 natively: <a href="https://github.com/simonrob/email-oauth2-proxy">https://github.com/simonrob/email-oauth2-proxy</a>. No need for your client to know about OAuth at all.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:00:01 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052409<dc:creator>sir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052409</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052409</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by interroboink in "Winding down Google Sync and Less Secure Apps support"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>My heart skipped a beat when I read this — I have various scripts and things that interact with Gmail.<p>But it's okay. App passwords will still work, it seems. This is just removal of "Less Secure Apps" support, using the account's plain account user/password.<p>I shudder to think how much automation would die if Google truly killed off everything but OAuth.<p>I don't like the complexity OAuth. I enjoyed this Perl module documentation[1] that breaks down how the dang thing works, clearly written by someone as exasperated as me (:<p>[1] <a href="https://metacpan.org/dist/LWP-Authen-OAuth2/view/lib/LWP/Authen/OAuth2/Overview.pod" rel="nofollow">https://metacpan.org/dist/LWP-Authen-OAuth2/view/lib/LWP/Aut...</a></p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 06:57:52 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052394<dc:creator>interroboink</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052394</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052394</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by zamfi in "Culture Change at Google"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Is any company still like this?<p>I was at Google in ‘06-07, and again ‘09-11, and already there were obvious differences. You just can’t scale “total internal transparency” when the company doubles in size every year.<p>And at some point you need just plain-old-“good” engineers to make the A/B tests happen and all the other stuff that doesn’t excite the PhDs. And at some point you need product people too, because you start to build products you’re not in the target audience for. And at some point your employees aren’t all going to be fabulously wealthy from an upcoming IPO, and so they’ll start playing political games for coveted titles and $1M+ comp so they too can have their house in Tahoe.<p>At some point the real world just gets in the way.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 06:21:56 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052144<dc:creator>zamfi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052144</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39052144</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by Ozzie_osman in "We migrated our PostgreSQL database with 11 seconds downtime"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>We did a similar migration (somewhat larger database) with ~20 seconds of downtime and much less work... using the magic of AWS RDS Blue-Green Deployments [1]. Surprised they aren't mentioned in the thread yet.<p>Basically, you spin up a new Blue Green deployment with any desired changes (in our case, we were upgrading Postgres major from 13 to 15). While your blue configuration continues to serve traffic, AWS uses logical replication to keep the "green" deployment in-sync. You can keep modifying (or testing) the "green" deployment (eg you could load test it if you wanted to), as long as you don't do any writes to it (writes still have to go to your live, blue configuration, and are replicated to green).<p>When you're ready, you run the "switch" command, and AWS does a few things for you: run checks to ensure blue/green are in sync, stops writes and connections, waits a few seconds to ensure replication is caught up, renames your database, then allows connections/writes again. We had less than 20 seconds of downtime, by our count. And, we had a primary and several read replicas and AWS successfully switched the full configuration over with no hiccups. You don't even need to switch your configuration because AWS swaps the database URLs for you. Green becomes blue, blue becomes old blue, and when you're ready, you delete "old blue".<p>Highly recommend! They do have some restrictions (for instance, not sure if it would work if you're switching accounts, etc).<p>1. <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/blue-green-deployments.html" rel="nofollow">https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/blue-...</a></p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:14:47 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39049904<dc:creator>Ozzie_osman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39049904</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39049904</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by intended in "Remote work doesn't seem to affect productivity, Fed study finds"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>I would add one major change that the work from home experiment has achieved - its made the opportunity cost of the work commute clear. This is a time cost paid for by the worker.<p>As you stated, this is variable.<p>If you have a short commute, or you like it, or you get some exercise - office is great.<p>If you hate your commute, if its 3 hours in pollution and traffic - not so much.<p>Earlier the position was that WFH was not possible. Now we know it is, and I hazard that this change isn't factored in job postings.<p>Considering what an hour of time means in this era, its not a trivial cost. This means an hour which could be spent just unwinding, studying, on hobbies, procrastinating, whatever.<p>If you have any drive, or strong interests, thats time you would want to spend on something other than a commute.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 11:36:56 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39040568<dc:creator>intended</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39040568</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39040568</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by epolanski in "Remote work doesn't seem to affect productivity, Fed study finds"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>The fundamental issue I see in this debate is a lack of sensibility and nuance in human nature.<p>The whole matter is debated (understandably in a way) on big numbers and averages.<p>I could write a long post but I'll cut it short to this paragraph stating that humans differ.<p>For some commuting is stressful, the offices are noisy and full of distractions and those individuals may thrive in a remote setup. There's people that work in the opposite way. Their house offer many distractions from laundry to videogames. Some people require micro management and constant oversight some tilt in such environments.<p>Some teams require a lot of meaningful in-person interactions, brainstorming sessions or work chats around the coffee machine. Some teams thrive with good central top/down planning and workload splitting where syncing isn't very important.<p>At the end of the day the decision C-suite have to make when planning projects is not remote vs non-remote and apply blindly rather in forming teams with people that by their own nature or preferences will thrive in the setup that's decided.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 11:09:47 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39040403<dc:creator>epolanski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39040403</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39040403</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by thedrake in "Which word begins with "y" and looks like an axe in this picture? (2017)"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>I was the one who solved this. It was an exciting time</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 07:39:58 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39039055<dc:creator>thedrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39039055</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39039055</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by mise_en_place in "Losing my son"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>The cruelest thing of all is that, technically speaking, his son is still alive. I’d imagine this to be far more torturous.<p>I have lost many close family members, but they all lost their biological lives. This just seems to be one of the worst experiences you could go through.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 05:02:16 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39038078<dc:creator>mise_en_place</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39038078</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39038078</guid></item></channel></rss>