<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>黑客新闻：最佳评论</title><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments<description>黑客新闻 RSS</description><docs> https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>人力资源服务 v2.1.1</generator><lastbuilddate> 2024 年 1 月 21 日星期日 23:49:58 +0000 </lastbuilddate><atom:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by matejn in "Password may not contain: select, insert, update, delete, drop"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>噢！我把那根绳子放在那里了！这是管理层的要求，但我仍然不知道为什么。该网站不存储任何密码，它基本上只是外部帐户管理的一个很好的界面。<p>我听说有传言称，一些旧版应用程序的登录字段有奇怪的验证，因此学生无法使用包含某些字符串的密码登录。但我实际上不知道任何例子。</p> ]]>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 21 Jan 2024 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate><link/> https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39079030<dc:creator>马泰因</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39079030</comments><guid ispermalink="false"> https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39079030 </guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by matsemann in "Password may not contain: select, insert, update, delete, drop"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>不能包含“脚本”。<p>我在十几岁的时候就黑了一个大型社交平台（Nettby.no），因为他们刚刚删除了所有禁止的单词，包括<script>. I instead wrote <scr<script>ipt> in my profile bio, and after their removal I had a valid html tag injected into the webpage and full control of anyone visiting my page..</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 14:32:04 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078748<dc:creator>matsemann</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078748</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39078748</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by Brajeshwar in "Vistex CEO Sanjay Shah dies on stage after freak accident"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>I know this is going to be voted down. I’m always scared of how things get done here in India -- not only because they are careless or trying to reduce cost -- but because of the utter lack of importance given to human lives. Unfortunately, with an overwhelmed legal system, most of us, especially ordinary people, cannot even pursue legal action when an accident happens.<p>I’ve seen, heard, and experienced people doing their job just barely enough to reach a stage of “it works,” popularly known in the colloquial term as, “Chalta Hain.” This is more prominent in works such as the ad-hoc stage creation, pop-up kitchens, and the like.<p>This incident is sad, and I hope people learn from it and will prevent the other 100 such accidents.<p>My Condolences.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 05:59:01 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39076016<dc:creator>Brajeshwar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39076016</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39076016</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by gfodor in "Nightshade: An offensive tool for artists against AI art generators"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Huge market for snake oil here. There is no way that such tools will ever win, given the requirements the art remain viewable to human perception, so even if you made something that worked (which this sounds like it doesn’t) from first principles it will be worked around immediately.<p>The only real way for artists or anyone really to try to hold back models from training on human outputs is through the law, ie, leveraging state backed violence to deter the things they don’t want. This too won’t be a perfect solution, if anything it will just put more incentives for people to develop decentralized training networks that “launder” the copyright violations that would allow for prosecutions.<p>All in all it’s a losing battle at a minimum and a stupid battle at worst. We know these models can be created easily and so they will, eventually, since you can’t prevent a computer from observing images you want humans to be able to observe freely.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 19:53:47 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071577<dc:creator>gfodor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071577</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071577</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by tedivm in "NASA loses contact with Ingenuity Mars helicopter"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>This is pretty sad but also pretty amazing. The original plan was for five flights of around 90 seconds each, and it looks like it finally failed on flight 72 with a total from all flights of two hours, eight minutes and eighteen seconds of flight time. All of this in an extremely thin atmosphere.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 19:06:52 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071099<dc:creator>tedivm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071099</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39071099</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by 542458 in "Nightshade: An offensive tool for artists against AI art generators"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>This seems to introduce levels of artifacts that many artists would find unacceptable: <a href="https://twitter.com/sini4ka111/status/1748378223291912567" rel="nofollow">https://twitter.com/sini4ka111/status/1748378223291912567</a><p>The rumblings I'm hearing are that this a) barely works with last-gen training processes b) does not work at all with more modern training processes (GPT-4V, LLaVA, even BLIP2 labelling [1]) and c) would not be especially challenging to mitigate against even should it become more effective and popular. The Authors' previous work, Glaze, also does not seem to be very effective despite dramatic proclamations to the contrary, so I think this might be a case of overhyping an academically interesting but real-world-impractical result.<p>[1]: Courtesy of /u/b3sn0w on Reddit: <a href="https://imgur.com/cI7RLAq" rel="nofollow">https://imgur.com/cI7RLAq</a> <a href="https://imgur.com/eqe3Dyn" rel="nofollow">https://imgur.com/eqe3Dyn</a> <a href="https://imgur.com/1BMASL4" rel="nofollow">https://imgur.com/1BMASL4</a></p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 15:38:26 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068620<dc:creator>542458</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068620</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068620</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by elmerfud in "Ubisoft Says Out Loud: We Want People to Get Used to Not Owning What They Bought"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>If buying is not owning then piracy is not stealing.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 15:01:42 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068194<dc:creator>elmerfud</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068194</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068194</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by someotherperson in "Spotube: Open-source Spotify-Youtube client"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Piracy is largely a convenience issue, not just a financial issue. When Netflix's streaming platform rolled around people were largely happy to stop pirating, when Netflix's catalog fragmented across two dozen different services that forbid account sharing then piracy became a thing again for many people who stopped pirating.<p>I had a Paramount+ subscription (alongside Disney, Netflix, Amazon, Apple TV) and wanted to watch a certain TV show on my device. Oops, my device was out of date so I couldn't download the app. No problems, I'll update it. Oops, my account is set to an overseas address so I can't download the app. No problems, I'll change my account settings. Oops, the app won't log in because my DNS blocks ads. No problems, I'll add a bypass for this app. Oops, the app sucks and crashes when I navigate through the catalog too quickly. No problems, I'll make my search more specific. Oops, the buffering speed is horrendous and scrubbing through the video crashes the app.<p>Guess what I did? Uninstalled the app and searched for a pirated version of the TV show. A minute later it was streaming fine on my device.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 14:51:48 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068087<dc:creator>someotherperson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068087</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39068087</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by swozey in "Spotube: Open-source Spotify-Youtube client"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>The lengths that literal engineers will go to to not have to pay $10/mo for music or $3 to rent a movie in 4k immediately.<p>Can't believe I have adult friends who make 70-300k and they still pirate based on money, not quality/directors-cuts/anti-cheats, etc. I quit pirating when I got a real job and could afford to pay developers and movie teams for their effort.<p>I write software. I want to get paid too, right? Why shouldn't they?<p>And I pirated EVERYTHING as a kid/teenager. I had no money. Sketch Russian warez site? I'm in!</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 14:37:32 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067937<dc:creator>swozey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067937</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067937</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by zillanovikov in "Amazon has taken down the Sad Bastard Cookbook"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Zilla here (one of the Sad Bastard Cookbook authors). Thanks so much for your support ... I'm lowkey dropping "front page of Hacker News" when I talk to Amazon Service reps now, in the vague hope they have any power to actually help me. I think I've reached at least one real person, but in the days of AI voice chat, who can tell?<p>Many of you asked why we use Amazon as the exclusive printer/distributor of the print edition. Variations of this happened to basically every self-pub author I've met, so why didn't I use another platform?<p>1) Reach. As Ma8ee pointed out, there's literally dozens of people buying books online but not on Amazon. If I want readers to find it, I need to be on Amazon. Bonus, one of the most important controlling factors in new people finding your book is whether the Amazon promo algorithim suggests the book to them, so any sale off Amazon doesn't contribute to building an avalanche. The game's rigged, but it's the only game in town.<p>2) Money/quality. Last time I checked (few years back, things might have changed), Draft2Digital print books were bad quality. Ingram print books are decent quality but their calculation for printing fees and royalties means they usually don't pay out at nearly the same rate. I've not compared directly for the Cookbook, but for Instant Classic, it's the difference between making a couple dollars or a couple cents. We did it for Instant Classic as a service for people who despise Amazon, but the royalties from the Cookbook are a substantial factor in "eating" and "making rent" for one of the Cookbook team, so there's a limit to how much I want to give away the print edition of the Cookbook. Especially if "giving it away" involves the reader paying Ingram, just not us. If anyone knows a print-on-demand distributor who pays out enough in royalties for authors to make money, please respond to this.<p>3) Distribution. We're small fry self-pub, without a big publishing house behind us. I've looked around for places which will take us on self-pub books and distribute them, and the options are pretty limited. I'm convinced we'd sell in brick-and-mortar stores, but that's typically not an option for self-pub unless you approach the owner of an independent bookshop on an individual basis. (We approached a couple proper distributors who accept query letters from non-traditionally published books, but they focused on specific genres and we weren't the right fit.) Basically, if you're not traditionally published, you're looking at Amazon, Ingram, or Draft2Digital to print and distribute your books. If anyone knows of other printer/distributors which take self-pub books, PLEASE tell me.<p>ETA: people are informing me that Ingram can make money, and that Lulu exists. I am investigating.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 14:20:21 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067769<dc:creator>zillanovikov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067769</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39067769</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by Reubend in "Spotube: Open-source Spotify-Youtube client"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>While it's nice to have an open source client, please think twice about bypassing the premium subscription/ads to listen for free.<p>Musician deserve to be paid for their work, and it's not fair to them to bypass all of the mechanisms to do that. Spotify doesn't pay musicians well, but there are still indie artists making a living from it nonetheless.<p>I hear a lot of people these days complaining about ads, and that's totally fair. But when it comes time to pay for content, those people rarely are willing to pony up. You can see this happening with journalism, music, apps, etc.<p>Similarly, most people hate subscriptions, but you can always buy music directly if you don't want to subscribe! A lot of smaller artists provide ways to purchase their music that give them a large percentage of the proceeds, and you can get the music DRM-free if that's something you care about.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:41:20 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066258<dc:creator>Reubend</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066258</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066258</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by radiator in "Retired teacher's pension stopped as provider refuses to believe she is not dead"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>> ... asked to confirm that they are not the same deceased stranger every 12 months since the system, administered by Capita, does not log a disproved link.<p>This is a bug in their system. Rather than fixing it, they prefer repeatedly and unashamedly asking old people whether they are dead.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:39:48 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066251<dc:creator>radiator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066251</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066251</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by bayindirh in "Spotube: Open-source Spotify-Youtube client"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Nifty.<p>Please be aware that this is not a "spotify client" per se. It gets the data from Spotify, and plays the audio from YouTube.<p>It's an interesting invention, and worthy of the first page, if you ask me.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:25:14 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066175<dc:creator>bayindirh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066175</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39066175</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by miellaby in "What's that touchscreen in my room?"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>I like how the author is surprised by the technological aberration that form Linux powered home appliances. A node server to power and publish over wifi a web site, an API, a web socket, while the site is being displayed by a outdated webview engine within an heavily constrained terminal which cant be reused for anything else. That's... the norm.<p>All this is very common. And yet displaying a couple of digits and a bar graph could be done with a pair of microcontrollers communicating onto some wired bus.<p>With the power supplies of this era, this pair of devices probably pumps 16w idle. Running 24/24 7/7, they probably consume as much as a small fridge as a whole. The LCA of the solution must be consterning as well, especially compared with few one dollard microcontrollers.<p>The worst of all is that this whole mess turned into bricks probably 3 years after it was installed, maybe less.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 07:14:33 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065412<dc:creator>miellaby</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065412</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065412</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by jonathanlydall in "What's that touchscreen in my room?"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>A few years ago I came to the realisation that if you want people to be more environmentally conscious or economical in terms of utility consumption, (electricity, water, gas, etc), they need far better data than a single figure per month.<p>You want to be able to see usage to a resolution of at most 5 minutes.<p>That way people can spot things like “having my electric heater on for those couple of hours used more electricity than all my lights use for a month”.<p>I have an inverter and solar panels in my place (very common now in South Africa middle class homes due to unreliable electricity producer) and I can see a full history of electricity usage.<p>It’s easy for me to see where I can improve my efficiency or why my consumption was so high.<p>It’s still only an overall figure though, so you have to do an informed assumption as to what caused the consumption.<p>For example it’s obvious that the 3kw draw for about an hour or so after I shower is the geyser heating itself back up. I can see from the usage stats that my battery was depleted from the night, that the solar production is still low due to my showering in the early morning and that the energy was thus coming from the grid (the inverter records all these figures).<p>It is then obvious that I can very simply save money on electricity by putting a timer on my geyser so that it only heats after 10am or so, once the sun is high enough for solar production to cover the energy usage.<p>Now I just wish I had something as convenient for monitoring water consumption.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 07:02:35 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065359<dc:creator>jonathanlydall</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065359</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39065359</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by josu in "What's that touchscreen in my room?"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>>DATE & TIME ARE ALWAYS CORRECT AND NEVER NEED TO BE ADJUSTED<p>Reads like a quote from a Philip K. Dick book.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 01:08:49 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063570<dc:creator>josu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063570</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063570</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by rmm in "Thailand discovers nearly 15M tonnes of lithium"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>This is my wheelhouse (mining engineer) and sorry to say this is bunk from what i can see.<p>Its not 15M Tonnes of Lithium. Its 15M Tonnes of lithium containing ore, with an average grade of 0.4% (which i also question without seening core results).<p>Also terms such as "resource" and "reserve" have very specific meaning in mining (to do with economic viability of deposity/ level of confidence) and this is by no way a "reserve".<p>Most likely overzealous government minister/media hyper. (sorry to rain on parade!)</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 23:57:14 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063078<dc:creator>rmm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063078</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39063078</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by orbisvicis in "Fujitsu bugs that sent innocent people to prison were known "from the start""]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>"I [Paul Patterson, co-CEO of Fujitsu's European division] am surprised that that detail was not included in the witness statements given by Fujitsu staff to the Post Office and I have seen some evidence of editing witness statements by others"<p>How does this scandal keep getting worse and worse when the only thing to cover up is a contract for some poorly written software?<p>At this point I'm starting to suspect some underlying malfeasance yet to be discovered.</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 20:39:27 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39060821<dc:creator>orbisvicis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39060821</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39060821</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by wolverine876 in "Americans are spending billions on stuff they forget to cancel"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>The blame falls also on businesses which take money for services they don't deliver. They often know, and otherwise often could know, when subscribers are not using the service. If you're a business, you should earn your revenue, otherwise you are frauds. This particular behavior is little better than taking money and simply refusing to provide service. Don't tell me it's unintentional - you know what's happening and could easily stop it.<p>It should be shame that also falls on them, but somehow we give businesses a pass. No matter how awful or shameful, people say 'it's business' and those magic words absolve every evil. If you took monthly payment from your elderly neighbor to shovel their walk and it never snowed, it would be shameful to keep taking it - people's opinions of you would change negatively if they heard about it. If you said 'well, they have autopay setup and didn't stop it', you would look even worse!</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39059392<dc:creator>wolverine876</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39059392</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39059392</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by LeoPanthera in "Surf the web like it's 1999"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>If you set your HTTP proxy to "theoldnet.com" with port 1999, and add an exclusion for "web.archive.org", then all your web pages will come from 1999, via the Wayback Machine.<p>You can pick a different year by changing the port.<p>Edit: It may have been hugged to death...</p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 18:03:03 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058806<dc:creator>LeoPanthera</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058806</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058806</guid></item><item><title><![CDATA[New comment by maliker in "Thailand discovers nearly 15M tonnes of lithium"]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<p>Looks like existing worldwide reserves are 26M tons [0], so this is a big find.<p>[0] <a href="https://pubs.usgs.gov/periodicals/mcs2023/mcs2023-lithium.pdf" rel="nofollow">https://pubs.usgs.gov/periodicals/mcs2023/mcs2023-lithium.pd...</a></p>
]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 17:34:29 +0000</pubDate><link/>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058286<dc:creator>maliker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058286</comments><guid ispermalink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39058286</guid></item></channel></rss>